女士　女士　求你
Ma'am. Ma'am, please.
- 帮我一把　-不行不行
- Please, can you help me? - No no!
解决他们　解决他们
Check them all. Check them all.
好吧
Okay.
兄弟我带你出去
I'm gonna get you out of here, bud.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
快点　下士　快走
Come on, corporal. Move out!
听着　如果你要醒过来　求你马上醒过来
Listen to me. If you're gonna wake up, I need you to do it now.
可以吗　快醒醒
Okay? Now.
求你了兄弟　给我点提示　随便什么都行
Please, man, just show me a sign. Anything.
求你了　瑞克
Please, Rick.
这地方要陷落了
The place is coming down!
撤退　所有人员都撤退
Fall back! All units fall back.
我
I'm…
没事
I'm okay.
《行尸走肉》
达里尔　你掩护后面
Daryl, you cover the back.
有人吗
Hello?
- 有人吗　-注意门口
- Hello? - Watch those doors.
小心行尸
Watch for walkers.
有人吗
Hello?
有没有谁被感染
Anybody infected?
有个人被感染了
One of our group was.
他没撑到这
He didn't make it.
为什么来这　你们要干什么
Why are you here? What do you want?
一个机会
A chance.
这年头这也算是奢望了
That's asking an awful lot these days.
我知道
I know.
你们都得做个血液检测
You all submit to a blood test.
检测完才能进来
That's the price of admission.
可以
We can do that.
把行李都弄进来　马上
You got stuff to bring in, you do it now.
这门要是关了　就开不了
Once this door closes, it stays closed.
维　密封大门
Vi, seal the main entrance.
关闭这里的电源
Kill the power up here.
我是瑞克·格兰姆斯
Rick Grimes.
我是埃德温·詹纳博士
Dr. Edwin Jenner.
博士们四处走动时都拿着枪吗
Doctors always go around packing heat like that?
外面躺着很多行尸呢　我很清楚
There were plenty left lying around. I familiarized myself.
不过你们看上去没什么威胁
But you look harmless enough.
除了你
Except you.
我会盯着你
I'll have to keep my eye on you.
我们在地下吗
Are we underground?
你有幽闭恐怖症吗
Are you claustrophobic?
- 有点　-别去想就不怕
- A little. - Try not to think about it.
维　把大厅的灯点亮
Vi, bring up the lights in the big room.
欢迎来到第五区
Welcome to zone 5.
其他人在哪儿
Where is everybody?
其他博士和员工呢
The other doctors, the staff?
就是我
I'm it.
这儿只有我
It's just me here.
那你刚跟谁说话
What about the person you were speaking with?
维
Vi?
维　跟大家打个招呼
Vi, say hello to our guests.
欢迎下大家
Tell them… welcome.
大家好　欢迎你们
Hello, guests. Welcome.
这里就剩下我
I'm all that's left.
让大家失望了
I'm sorry.
这有什么意义　如果我们被感染了
What's the point? If we were infected,
肯定会发烧
we'd all be running a fever.
我把你们放进来　已经违反了所有规定
I've already broken every rule in the book letting you in here.
至少让我守一点点规矩
Let me just at least be thorough.
可以了
All done.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
她几天没吃东西了
She hasn't eaten in days.
我们也一样
None of us have.
好吧
Fine.
知道吗　在意大利
You know, in Italy,
吃饭时　孩子们也可以喝点小酒
children have a little bit of wine with dinner.
在法国也是
And in France.
要是卡尔在意大利或法国
Well, when Carl is in Italy or France,
- 那他也可以喝点　-这有什么大不了　拜托
- he can have some then. - What's it gonna hurt? Come on.
通融一下
Come on.
怎么
What?
给　小伙子
There you are, young lad.
这才是我儿子
That's my boy. That's my boy.
- 乖孩子　-好难喝
- Good boy. - Yuck.
真难喝
That tastes nasty.
你还是喝点果汁吧　伙计
Well, just stick to sour pop there, bud.
- 没说你　格伦　-什么
- Not you, Glenn. - What?
你继续喝　小伙子
Keep drinking, little man.
我想瞧瞧你能脸红到什么地步
I want to see how red your face can get.
好像还没正式感谢招待我们的主人
It seems to me we haven't thanked our host properly.
他为我们所做的远不止这些
He is more than just our host.
- 干　干　-敬你一杯　博士　干
- Hear hear! - Here's to you, doc. Booyah!
- 干　-谢谢你
- Booyah! - Thank you!
干
Booyah!
你啥时准备告诉我们这里的事　博士
So when are you gonna tell us what the hell happened here, doc?
其他的那些博士
All the… the other doctors.
本该在这里研究对策
that were supposed to be figuring out what happened.
- 他们到哪去了　-咱们在庆祝　肖恩
- Where are they? - We're celebrating, Shane.
现在别说这些
Don't need to do this now.
慢着　这正是我们此行的目的吧
Whoa, wait a second. This is why we're here, right?
你的目的
This was your move…
就是要寻找答案吧
supposed to find all the answers.
结果呢
Instead we…
我们找到他
we found him.
只找到一个人　为什么
Found one man. Why?
灾难降临后
Well, when things got bad,
很多人都走了
a lot of people just left.
找他们的家人去了
Went off to be with their families.
后来形势恶化
And when things got worse,
军事防御被击溃
when the military cordon got overrun,
其他人都逃跑了
the rest bolted.
所有的人吗
Every last one?
不　很多人无法面对外面的世界
No, many couldn't face walking out the door.
他们别无选择
They… opted out.
许多人都自杀了
There was a rash of suicides.
真是不堪回首
That was a bad time.
你没走
You didn't leave.
为什么
Why?
我一直在工作
I just kept working.
想做点有用的事
Hoping to do some good.
你真扫大家的兴　伙计
Dude, you are such a buzzkill, man.
中心大多地方都断电了
Most of the facility is powered down.
包括宿舍　所以你们只能在这凑合
Including housing, so you'll have to make do here.
沙发挺舒服
The couches are comfortable,
喜欢的话仓库里还有吊床
But there are cots in storage if you like.
大厅那边有个娱乐室　孩子们可能会喜欢
There's a rec room down the hall that you kids might enjoy.
只是不要玩电子游戏　好吗
Just don't plug in the video games, okay?
任何要用电的都不行　同样的
or anything that draws power. The same applies…
如果你们要洗澡　用热水好了
If you shower, go easy on the hot water.
热水
Hot water?
千真万确
That's what the man said.
安德莉亚
Andrea?
来
That's it.
慢慢来　吐出来
That's it. Get it out.
没事了
There you go.
老天
Oh… god.
一切都没了
Everything's gone.
喝下去总比吐出来好吧
It's always better going down than coming up, huh?
我不是说酒　戴尔
I don't mean the wine, Dale.
结束了　一切都没了
You know, it's over. There's nothing left.
你不觉得吗
Don't you see that?
我觉得
Oh, I… I see a…
这倒是个重新开始的机会
A chance to make a new start.
老天啊　戴尔
Oh my god, Dale.
戴尔　你没看到詹纳的表情吗
Dale, didn't you see the look on Jenner's face?
相信我吧
Hear what I'm saying.
一切都没了
There's nothing left.
血液检验怎么样了
How's the blood?
一切正常
No surprises.
我是来谢谢你的
I came to thank you.
你谢过了
You did.
你没事吧
You all… you all right?
你不知道是什么样
You don't know what it's like.
你不知道外面世界是什么样
You don't know what it's like out there.
你以为你知道　其实不然
You may think you do, but you don't.
我们在外面会死
We'd have died out there.
这只是时间问题
It was only a matter of time.
行尸太多了
There's too many of those things.
我的儿子
My… my boy…
我的妻子　我从没…
My… my wife, I never…
我从没告诉过他们我真实的想法
I never told 'em what I really thought.
甚至连一点暗示都没　只是…
I never even hinted, just…
只是闷在心里
Just kept it in.
闷在心里　让大家心怀希望
Kept it in and kept us moving, you know.
闷在心里　让大家心怀…
Just kept it in. Kept us…
不会有事
It'll all be okay.
都会好的
It'll be okay.
有什么好书吗
Any good books?
够我们看上好几年了
Enough to keep us busy for years.
好了　孩子们　该睡觉了
All right. Come on, kids, it's bedtime.
宝贝儿　你们去睡前祈祷吧　我再看会书
Baby, go say your prayers. I'm gonna browse a bit.
来吧
Come on.
这是你们第一次能睡个好觉
This is the first night we might actually get some real sleep.
真是奇迹　不是吗
It's a miracle, isn't it?
老天　你吓死我了
Jesus, you scared me.
我要跟你说些事
I'm gonna tell you a few things.
你给我好好听着
And you're gonna listen to me.
现在不行
Now is not the time.
得了　那又该什么时候说
Come on. When is it ever the time?
你怎么能这么对我
How can you treat me like this?
- 你开玩笑吧　-不
- You're kidding, right? - No. Huh-uh.
因为你告诉我　我丈夫死了
Because you told me my husband was dead.
我没有撒谎　好吗　真的没有
I didn't lie to you, all right? I didn't.
你知道医院里的情况吗
Do you know what it was like there?
听我说　一切都崩溃了
Stop. Things were falling apart.
他们在过道里杀人
They were slaughtering people in the hallways.
就是场大屠杀　到处都有行尸
It was a massacre. There were walkers everywhere.
- 你就这么扔下他了　-大家都跑了
- So you left him? - Everybody else ran.
没有医生　只剩下我
There were no doctors there. It was just me.
他身上连着仪器　我不知道该怎么办
He was hooked up to machines and I did not know what to do.
我甚至贴着他的胸膛听过
I even took my ear and I put it on his chest.
想听听有没有心跳　结果没有
And I listened for a heartbeat and I did not hear one.
我也不知道为什么
And I-I-I-I… I don't know why.
也许是此起彼伏的枪声　我也不知道
Maybe it was gunfire. I don't know what it was,
但他没可能活下来　绝对没可能
But there was no way he could've survived that. No way.
- 但他活下来了　-对　但我还得考虑你们
- He did. - Yeah, but then I had y'all to think about, didn't I?
还有你和卡尔
I had you and Carl,
- 我得考虑你们的安危　-不
- and I needed to think about… - okay. No no.
我得把你们平安送到亚特兰大
I had to get you guys safe to Atlanta.
我必须这样　别这样
That's what I had to do. Just stop.
你好好想想
If you thought for one second.
如果他还活着　你会离开吗
that he was still alive, would you have come?
这么说我救了你
So I saved your life…
你和你儿子　我救了你们
You and your little boy's. That's what I did.
是吧
Right?
好吧
Okay.
如果要我和他交换　我也愿意
And if I could've traded places with him, I would have.
我现在就愿意和他换
I would trade places with him right now because…
不不不　你听好
No no no, you…
- 我爱你　-不　你喝醉了
- I love you. Shh shh. - No. No, you're drunk.
- 我爱你　-你喝醉了
- I love you. - No, you're drunk.
我知道你也爱我
And I know there were some things that say that you love me too.
不然的话
Because there's no way that.
你不会对我这么冷淡
you could've been with me the way that you were.
肖恩　住手
Shane. Shane. Shane!
听着　你爱我
Listen. You love me.
放开我　快放开我
Get your hands off me. Get your hands off me.
- 我爱你　这里没别人　-不要　快住手
- I love you. There's nobody here. - Please! No!
别这样　洛莉　没关系的
Stop, Lori. It's all right. Just…
我们不用再害怕了
We don't have to be afraid anymore.
我们在这很安全
We're safe here.
好吗
All right?
- 早　-你宿醉了吗
- Morning. - Are you hungover?
- 妈就说你会　-妈妈说得对
- Mom said you'd be. - Mom is right.
妈妈总说得对
Mom has that annoying habit.
糊状的鸡蛋　但还算美味
Eggs. Powdered, but… but I do 'em good.
我想你吃不出来
I bet you can't tell.
蛋白质有助于治宿醉
Protein helps the hangover.
这都哪儿来的
Where'd all this come from?
- 詹纳给的　-能帮我一下吗
- Jenner. - could you help me, please?
他觉得我们用得着
He thought we could use it.
- 谢了　-至少是少部分人
- Thank you. - Some of us, at least.
再也不要让我喝酒了
Don't ever ever ever let me drink again.
感觉和我一样糟糕吗
Feel as bad as I do?
比你更糟
Worse.
你怎么了
The hell happened to you?
看你那脖子
Your neck?
肯定是睡觉时弄到了
I must have done it in my sleep.
以前睡觉可没弄伤过啊
Never seen you do that before.
我也不知道
Me neither.
我不再是以前的我了
Not like me at all.
- 各位早　-博士早
- Morning.　- Hey, doc.
博士　我不想一大早上来就问你问题
Doctor, I don't mean to slam you with questions first thing…
但你还是会问
But you will anyway.
我们可不是来蹭饭的
We didn't come here for the eggs.
回放19号试验
Give me playback of TS-19.
Playback of TS-19.
很少人看过这些资料
Few people ever got a chance to see this.
没几个
Very few.
- 那是大脑吗　-一个杰出的大脑
- Is that a brain?　- An extraordinary one.
抛开结果不说的话
Not that it matters in the end.
展示内部放大视图
Take us in for E.I.V…
内部放大视图
Enhanced internal view.
那些亮斑是什么
What are those lights?
那是一个人的生命
It's a person's life…
经历　还有记忆
experiences, memories.
一切都在这里
It's everything.
所有的这些组织网络
Somewhere in all that organic wiring,
所有的这些亮斑
All those ripples of light,
造就了你
is you…
让你变得独一无二
The thing that makes you unique.
变得有人性
And human.
我还是听不懂
You don't make sense ever?
那些是神经突触
Those are synapses,
大脑中的电子脉冲
electric impulses in the brain.
运载着一切信息
that carry all the messages.
从你刚出生开始　它就控制着
They determine everything a person says.
你的所说所做和所想
does or thinks from the moment of birth.
直到你死亡
to the moment of death.
直到死亡　这是监测图像吗
Death? That's what this is, a vigil?
没错
Yes.
准确说是监测图像的回放
Or rather the playback of the vigil.
这人死了吗
This person died?
他是什么人
Who?
19号试验品
Test subject 19.
一个被咬　感染上病毒
Someone who was bitten and infected…
还自愿让我们记录下转变过程的人
and volunteered to have us record the process.
维　浏览项目一
Vi, scan forward to the first event.
浏览项目一
Scanning to first event.
那是怎么回事
What is that?
它就像脑膜炎一样感染大脑
It invades the brain like meningitis.
导致肾上腺出血
The adrenal glands hemorrhage,
大脑停止运作
the brian goes into shutdown,
然后到主要器官
then the major organs.
最后死亡
Then death.
你的过去与未来
Everything you ever were or ever will be…
都消逝了
Gone.
吉姆也会这样吗
Is that what happened to Jim?
没错
Yes.
两天前她失去了一个亲人
She lost somebody two days ago.
她妹妹
Her sister.
我也失去了亲人
I lost somebody too.
我知道这有多难受
I know how devastating it is.
浏览项目二
Scan to the second event.
Scanning to second event.
变异时间有长有短
The resurrection times vary wildly.
报告说　短的有三分钟
We had reports of it happening in as little as three minutes.
最长有八小时
The longest we heard of was eight hours.
至于这个病人
In the case of this patient,
是两小时一分
it was two hours, one minute…
零七秒
Seven seconds.
- 它让大脑重新运作吗　-不　只是脑干
- It restarts the brain?　- No, just the brain stem.
原理上说　是让行尸起来走动
Basically, it gets them up and moving.
但他们不是活的吗
But they're not alive?
你说说
You tell me.
和以前不同了
It's nothing like before.
大脑大部分都是黑暗的
Most of that brain is dark.
黑暗　毫无生机　说明死了
Dark, lifeless, dead.
大脑额叶　脑皮层
The frontal lobe, the neocortex,
属于人的那部分　没活过来
The human part… that doesn't come back.
让你活着的那部分
The you part.
只是一具没有思想　只由本能控制的躯壳
Just a shell driven by mindless instinct.
我的天啊　怎么了
God. What was that?
他朝那病人的头射了一枪
He shot his patient in the head.
是吧
Didn't you?
维　关闭主屏和工作台
Vi, power down the main screen and the workstations.
关闭主屏和工作台
Powering down main screen and workstations.
你也弄不清那是什么吧
You have no idea what it is, do you?
可能是细菌　病毒　寄生菌　或真菌
It could be microbial, viral, parasitic, fungal.
抑或是上帝的惩罚
Or the wrath of god?
可能吧
There is that.
一定有人知道些什么
Somebody must know something.
在某处的什么人
Somebody somewhere.
还有其他人　对吧　其他机构
There are others, right? Other facilities?
可能有吧
There may be some.
像我这样的人
People like me.
但你不知道　你怎么可能什么都不知道
But you don't know? How can you not know?
什么都没了
Everything went down.
通讯　上级指示　都没了
Communications, directives… all of it.
我已经活在黑暗中快一个月了
I've been in the dark for almost a month.
那么说　不光是这里
So it's not just here.
不管在哪都是一无所有了
There's nothing left anywhere? Nothing?
你其实是这个意思吧
That's what you're really saying, right?
天啊
Jesus.
哥们　我又想去大醉一场了
Man, I'm gonna get soon faced drunk again.
詹纳博士　我知道你已经很难做了
Dr. Jenner, I know this has been taxing for you.
我不想再问问题了　但是
And I hate to ask one more question, but…
那个钟
That clock…
正在倒计时
It's counting down.
数到零时会发生什么
What happens at zero?
地下室的发电机没燃料了
The basement generators… they run out of fuel.
然后呢
And then?
维　电力耗尽会发生什么事
Vi, what happens when the power runs out?
电力耗尽后
When the power runs out,
将会进行全面消毒
facility-wide decontamination will occur.
消毒　那意味着什么
Decontamination… what does that mean?
我不太喜欢詹纳他拒不开口
I don't like the way Jenner clammed up.
他就那么走开了
The way he just wandered off like that.
他怎么了　说真的　伙计
What's wrong with him? Seriously, man,
他傻了　嗑药了　还是怎么了
Is he nuts, medicated, what?
那边
In there.
去那边看看
Check that way.
肖恩
Shane.
空的
It's empty.
- 开启应急照明　-这怎么回事
- Emergency lighting on. - What the hell is this?
喂　你们关了灯吗
Hey, you guys kill the lights?
- 不　它自己灭了　-有什么发现吗
- Nah, it just went ou. - Anything?
有　一堆停止运转的发电机
Yeah, a lot of dead generators.
和数不清的空燃料桶
and more empty fuel drums than I can count.
肯定不会只剩这一个
It can't be down to just that one.
妈妈　出什么事了吗
Mom? Something wrong?
没事　只不过
Nothing. It's just…
空调停了
the air conditioning stopped.
时间有限　但我已经尽最大努力了
I did the best I could in the time that I had.
我希望你能以此为傲
I hope you'd be proud of that.
我们总以为还有很长路要走
We always think there's gonna be more time…
却不知不觉已到尽头
…then it runs out.
空调怎么停了
Why is the air off?
- 还有房间里的灯也灭了　-怎么回事
- and the lights in our room? - What's going on?
为什么所有电器都停了
Why is everything turned off?
正在优先化能源耗用
Energy use is being prioritized.
空调不是最重要的吗　还有灯呢
Air isn't a priority? And lights?
这不是我决定的　第五区在自行关闭
It's not up to me. Zone 5 is shutting itself down.
喂　喂　这话是什么意思
Hey! Hey, what the hell does that mean?
兄弟　我问你话呢
Hey man, I'm talking to you.
什么叫自行关闭
What do you mean it's shutting itself down?
一所建筑怎么有这能耐
How can a building do anything?
- 你不知道的事还多着呢　-瑞克
- You'd be surprised. - Rick?
詹纳　怎么回事
Jenner, what's happening?
系统正在终止一切非必需设备
The system is dropping all the nonessential uses of power.
为了尽可能保证
It's designed to keep the.
电脑运行时间　直到最后一刻
computers running to the last possible second.
当剩余时间接近半小时　程序就会启动
That started as we approached the half-hour mark.
计划之中
Right on schedule.
- 法国人　-什么
- It was the French. - what?
据我所知　他们坚持到了最后
They were the last ones to hold out as far as I know.
当我们的人或夺门而去
While our people were bolting out the doors.
或在过道里自杀时
and committing suicide in the hallways,
他们一直留守在实验室里
they stayed in the labs till the end.
他们自认为快要找出解决之道了
They thought they were close to a solution.
然后呢
What happened?
跟这里情况一样
The same thing that's happening here.
电力耗尽
No power grid.
弹尽粮绝
Ran out of juice.
整个世界的运转都依赖于矿物燃料
The world runs on fossil fuel.
真是荒天下之大谬
I mean, how stupid is that?
- 我告诉你　-见鬼去吧　肖恩　我才不在乎
- Let me tell you… - To hell with it, Shane. I don't even care.
洛莉　去收拾东西　大家都收拾下东西
Lori, grab our things. Everybody, get your stuff.
我们现在就走
We're getting out of here now!
好
Oh, okay.
什么声音
What's that?
怎么了
距消毒程序启动还有三十分钟
30 minutes to decontamination.
博士　这是怎么回事
Doc, what's going on here?
你们大家都听见瑞克说的了
Everybody, y'all heard Rick.
收拾东西　咱们马上离开　快
Get your stuff and let's go! Go now! Go!
- 我们走　-快点
- Let's go. - Come on!
不
No.
你是把我们锁在里面了吗
Did you just lock us in?
他把我们锁在里面了
He just locked us in!
三十分钟时限开始　我在记录中
We've hit the 30-minute window. I am recording.
- 卡尔　-妈妈
- Carl. - Mom!
- 你个狗娘养的　-肖恩
- You son of a bitch. - Shane!
- 你快放我们出去　-不　停手　不要
- You let us out of here! - No, stop. Don't!
- 满口胡言的　-不　不不
- You lying… - No no no no!
等等　别这样
Wait, no! No, don't do it.
詹纳　立刻开门
Hey, Jenner, open that door now.
没用的　上面的出口全都关闭了
There's no point. Everything topside is locked down.
紧急通道也封锁了
The emergency exits are sealed.
那他妈的就打开啊
Well, open the damn things.
我无法控制　是电脑操控的
That's not something I control. The computers do.
我告诉过你们　前门一旦关闭
I told you once that front door closed,
就再也无法开启了　你们当时都听见了
it wouldn't open again. You heard me say that.
- 这样更好一点　-怎样
- It's better this way. - What is?
28分钟以后会怎样
What happens in 28 minutes?
- 28分钟以后会怎样　-够了
- What happens in 28 minutes??! - COME ON!
你知道这是什么地方吗
You know what this place is?!
这里面存放的东西
We protected the public.
危害性相当强大
from very nasty stuff!
生化武器　天花病毒
Weaponized smallpox!
能夺去半数国民生命的埃博拉菌株
Ebola strains that could wipe out half the country!
那可是你们死都不想泄露出去的东西
Stuff you don't want getting out! Ever!
发生灾难性电力故障时
In the event of a catastrophic power failure…
比如在恐怖袭击中
in a terrorist attack, for example…
系统会启动HIT　以禁止任何有机体离开
H.I.T.s are deployed to prevent any organisms from getting out.
HIT
H.I.T.s?
- 维　解释下　-HIT
- Vi, define. - HITs…
指强脉冲温压油气炸弹
high-impulse thermobaric fuel-air explosives.
包含两阶段气溶胶点火装置
cocoists of a two-stage aerosol ignition.
使其产生的冲击波　破坏力与持久性
that produces a blast wave of significantly greater power.
均优于所有已知炸药　仅次于核武器
and duration than any other known explosive except nuclear.
在真空压力下　于五千度至六千度间
The vacuum-pressure effect ignites the oxygen.
点燃氧气
between 5, 000 and 6, 000 degrees.
可导致极其惨重的人员伤亡
and is used when the greatest loss of life.
和财产损失
and damage to structures is desired.
它会点燃空气
It sets the air on fire.
毫无痛苦
No pain.
再无忧伤　悲痛
An end to sorrow, grief…
懊悔
regret.
一切到此为止
Everything.
他妈的把门打开
Open the damn door!
让开
Out of my way!
达里尔
Daryl!
顺其自然吧
You should've left well enough alone.
- 会好过许多　-谁会好过
- it would've been so much easier. - Easier for who?
所有人都会　你们清楚外面的情况
All of you. You know what's out there…
生不能安寝　死不得安息
A short, brutal life and an agonizing death.
你妹妹　叫什么来着
Your… your sister… what was her name?
- 艾米　-艾米
- Amy. - Amy.
你明白最终会是怎样的下场
You know what this does.
亲眼所见
You've seen it.
你想让妻子和儿子落得那种下场吗
Is that really what you want for your wife and son?
我可不想这样
I don't want this.
毫无进展
Can't make a dent.
那些门都能经受火箭袭击
Those doors are designed to withstand a rocket launcher.
但你的脑袋可受不了
Well, your head ain't!
达里尔　达里尔
Daryl! Daryl!
后退　住手
Just back up! Back up!
你确实希望如此
You do want this.
昨天晚上你说过
Last night you said.
你知道你心爱的人迟早会死
you knew it was just a matter of time.
不过是时间问题
before everybody you loved was dead.
什么
What?
什么　你真这么说吗
What? You really said that?
那你之前说的大话算什么
After all your big talk?
我必须时刻保持希望
I had to keep hope alive, didn't I?
没有希望了
There is no hope.
- 从来就没有希望　-希望总是存在
- there never was. - There's always hope.
也许不是你　也许不在这
Maybe it won't be you, maybe not here,
但在其他地方总会有人…
But somebody somewhere…
所有的一切都完了　你还不明白吗
What part of "Everything is gone" Do you not understand?
听你朋友的吧　她明白这道理
Listen to your friend. She gets it.
这次我们经历的浩劫
This is what takes us down.
是灭绝之灾
This is our extinction event.
这样不对
This isn't right.
你不能把我们关在这
You can't just keep us here.
就那么一瞬间
One tiny moment…
千分之一秒　毫无痛苦
A millisecond. No pain.
我女儿不该这样死去
My daughter doesn't deserve to die like this.
这难道还不够仁慈
Wouldn't it be kinder,
不够怜悯吗　抱着你所爱的人
more compassionate to just hold your loved ones.
慢慢等待生命的终结
and wait for the clock to run down?
- 肖恩　住手　-闪开　瑞克
- Shane, no! - Out of the way, Rick!
你给我闪开　快开门
Stay out of my way! Open that door.
不然我让你脑袋开花　听到了吗
or I'm gonna blow your head off. Do you hear me?!
哥们　你不能做这种事
Brother, brother, this is not the way you do this.
- 这样我们出不去　-肖恩　你听他一句
- We will never get out of here. - Shane, you listen to him.
- 太迟了　-要是他死了
- It's too late. - He dies, we all…
我们都死定了　肖恩
we all die! Shane!
肖恩
Shane!
你够了吗　你闹完了吗
Are you done now? Are you done?
是的　我想我们都完了
Yeah, I guess we all are.
我觉得你在撒谎
I think you're lying.
- 什么　-你在撒谎
- What? - You're lying.
你说毫无希望
About no hope.
如果真是这样　你早和大家一起跑了
If that were true, you'd have bolted with the rest.
或者死了一了百了　但你没有
or taken the easy way out. You didn't.
你却做了更艰难的选择
You chose the hard path.
- 为什么　-无所谓了
- Why? - It doesn't matter.
有所谓　不可能无所谓
It does matter. It always matters.
别人逃走你却选择留下来
You stayed when others ran.
- 到底为什么　-不是我想留下
- Why? - Not because I wanted to.
我做过承诺
I made a promise…
对她
To her.
我的妻子
My wife.
19号试验品是你妻子
Test subject 19 was your wife?
她求我尽全力继续研究
She begged me to keep going as long as I could.
我怎么拒绝得了
How could I say no?
她就快死了
She was dying.
死的应该是我
It should've been me on that table.
我根本毫无价值
I wouldn't have mattered to anybody.
而她的死却是全世界的损失
She was a loss to the world.
见鬼　她是这儿的领导　而我只是下属
Hell, she ran this place. I just worked here.
她就是这个领域的奇才
In our field, she was an Einstein.
我呢　我不过是个无名小卒
Me? I'm just… Edwin Jenner.
她本可以有所作为
She could've done something about this.
而我不行
Not me.
你妻子没有选择
Your wife didn't have a choice.
而你却有　我们想要的
You do. That's… that's all we want…
只是一个选择　去赌一把
A choice, a chance.
让我们尽全力去尝试一下
Let us keep trying as long as we can.
我说了外门已封锁　我开不了
I told you topside's locked down. I can't open those.
快来
Come on!
- 快走　-快点　快走
- Let's go! - Come on, let's go!
- 快点　-快走
- Come on! - Move it! Move it!
- 快点走　-我们离开这儿　索菲亚
- Come on, let's go! - We're gonna get out of here, Sophia.
这是你的机会　去吧
There's your chance. Take it.
我很感谢
I'm grateful.
- 你总有一天会改变主意　-快点
- The day will come when you won't be. - Let's go!
我们只剩4分钟了　快走
Hey, we've got four minutes left! Come on!
- 快走　-不　我要留下
- Let's go. Let's go. - No no, I'm staying.
我要留下　亲爱的
I'm staying, sweetie.
- 你这是疯了　-不　我很理智
- But that's insane! - no, it's completely sane.
这么久以来从没这么理智过
For the first time in a long time.
我不想变成吉姆和艾米那样
I'm not ending up like Jim and Amy.
没时间争论了
There's no time to argue.
也没有意义　你们快出去
and no point, not if you want to get out.
出去吧　快走
Just get out. Get out.
T仔　快走　伙计
Dog. Come on, man.
快点　快走了
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
我也要留下
I'm staying too.
不　安德莉亚
Andrea, no.
- 你们先走　-快点
- Just go! Go! - Come on.
安德莉亚
Andrea,
艾米不希望你这样
This isn't what Amy would want for you.
她死了　你得快走
She's dead, and you need to leave.
- 快把门打开　-拜托
- Get them doors open! - Come on!
- 不行　-等一下
- It doesn't work! - Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
快试试看
Try it! Try it! Try it now!
- 快开啊　-跟紧我　宝贝儿
- Come on! Come on! - Stay close, sweetheart.
时间快到了
Time's almost up.
达里尔　小心
Daryl, look out!
T仔　快下来
Dog, get down! Get down!
- 老天　-这玻璃打不碎吗
- Jesus. - The glass won't break?
瑞克　我这里有东西可能有用
Rick, I have something that might help.
卡萝尔　指甲锉可派不上用处
Carol, I don't think a nail file's gonna do it.
你刚到营地时
Your first morning at camp,
我帮你洗制服时在口袋里找到这个
when I washed your uniform I found this in your pocket.
来吧
Come on.
小心
Look out!
- 快趴下　-见鬼
- Get down! Get down! - Shit?
好吧
Okay.
你赢了
You win.
- 你在做什么　-我说好吧
- What are you doing? - I said okay.
- 别开玩笑了　戴尔　-我没开玩笑
- Don't pull this, Dale. - I'm not pulling anything.
如果你留下　我也留下
If you're staying, I stay too.
他说的没错　我们都知道出去会有什么后果
He's right. We know what's waiting for us out there.
我不想独自去面对
I don't want to face it alone.
戴尔　见鬼的　你快出去
Dale, get the hell out.
我不想你留在这
I don't want you here.
太糟糕了　你不能这样
Too bad. See, you don't get to do that,
走进某人的生活
to… to come into somebody's life,
让他在乎你后又一走了之
make them care and then just check out.
我要留下
I'm staying.
这事就这么定了
The matter is settled.
等一下
Wait wait wait. Wait wait.
他们来了
They're coming.
他们出去了
They got out.
快点
Come on.
戴尔　卧倒　快卧倒
Dale, get down! Down!
到里面去　大家都卧倒
Get back! Everybody down! Down!
卧倒
Get down!
来吧　快来
Come on. Come on.
快点　上车
Come on. Come on. Get in, get in, get in.
快上车
Get in!